Veera Venkata Adabala

Big Data Engineer

Experienced and dynamic Big Data Engineer, devoted to maintaining reliable data warehouses for uninterrupted workflows and visualization. Communicates clearly with stakeholders and builds consensus around well-founded requirements. Willingness to take on added responsibilities to meet team goals

Contact

Address

Kakinada, Andhra Pradesh, 533006

Phone

903 200 2181

E-mail

vv.adabala@gmail.com

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in /avvrkrishna

Skills

- Analytical and Critical Thinking
- Problem Solving Skills
- Accountability
- Organization and Time Management
- Multi-Tasking Abilities
- Planning and Coordination

Software Skills

- Python3, Pyspark, SQL, SparkSQL, Unix Shell Scripting, EDA, RCA
- Jira, Bit-Bucket, Git,
 VScode, Snowflake, ETL,

Work History

2021-07 -Current

Big Data Engineer

Fractal Analytics, Bangalore, Karnataka

- Working on developing sql scripts and models using dbt to handle efficient automated transformations as part of ETL in format that can be further analyzed and utilized for Data Visualization and Decision Science Teams
- Designing efficient pipelines in Azure data factory as per requirements which processes dbt code from Azure storage
- Monitoring incoming data analytics requests, executed analytics and efficiently distributed results to support wireframe strategies
- Addressed ad hoc analytics requests and facilitated data acquisitions to support internal projects, special projects and investigations and Poc's

2018-03 -2021-07

Data Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services, Hyderabad, Telangana

- As data engineer, worked in Enterprise Data
 Analytics team for retail client designing ETL
 pipelines that process and transforms both
 Batch data and also Streamline data on daily
 basis
- Worked on building efficient scheduler jobs
 utilizing Apache Airflow for smooth processing
 for OLAP from Amazon S3 with various file
 formats viz., JSON, CSV to load data to

Airflow, dbt

- AWS: Athena, Redshift, EMR, S3, Glue, AWS Lambda
- Azure: Azure DevOps, Azure Repos, Azure Storage, Azure Data Factory
- Working knowledge on GCP services, Dataflow, Dataproc, Dataprep, Bigguery

Languages

English

Excellent

Hindi

Excellent

Telugu

Excellent

Interests

Badminton

Artificial Intelligence

Automation

Competitive Programming

Personal Projects

 Developed automation tools using Python for daily tasks

- Snowflake Data warehouse
- Designed and developed UDF's in Snowflake based on requirements using JavaScript for easy data processing and validations
- Contributed to internal activities for overall process improvements, efficiencies and innovation
- Compiled, cleaned and manipulated data for proper handling.

Accomplishments

- Achieved reduction of production downtime by introducing Automation Tool for repetitive tasks.
- Honored with LIREL award in recognition for being role model to fellow associates by following organization principles

Education

2013-09 - Bachelor's of Technology: Electrical And Electronics

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University -Kakinada

Certifications

2021-11	Snowflake Snowpro Core Certified
2021-08	Microsoft Certified in Azure Al Fundamentals
2021-08	Microsoft Certified in Azure Data Fundamentals
2021-06	Google Data Analytics Career Certificate

Additional Information

 Always believes in continuous learning process and loves to think out of the box